<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Wroclaw Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="welcome">Wroclaw, one of the most beautiful cities in Poland with many parks, boulvards, monuments. If you want to learn more about this climatic place, I invite you to a virtual journey.</string>
    <string name="start">Start the journey</string>
    <string name="category_top_attractions">Top</string>
    <string name="category_monuments">Monuments</string>
    <string name="category_public_places">Public Places</string>
    <string name="category_attractions_for_kids">Kids</string>
    <string name="category_restaurants">Food</string>
    <string name="wax_museum">Wax Museum</string>
    <string name="wax_museum_contact">2b New Street \n533 866 533 \nwww.wytworniafigur.pl</string>
    <string name="wax_museum_description">The Wax Museum is an enjoyable destination for children between 4 and 12 years of age. The Museum can also serve as a venue. The underground of Partisans\' Hill holds a variety of intriguing waxworks: Michael Jackson, Daniel Craig, best known for his role in the James Bond franchise, and Elizabeth Taylor, or the legendary Queen Cleopatra. The waxworks look really natural and realistic. The Wax Museum also holds a variety of figures from legends and fairy tales, popular films and cartoons. Spiderman is hanging just above Batman while the Lion King is looking at a crowd of Mignons. The likeable Monsters, Inc. are also there. Likewise, the Fellowship of the Ring and the Ice Age characters are represented in the Museum. The massive Hulk will make your heart shudder, whereas Shrek and his Fiona ore nothing to be frightened of. The children have a unique chance to find out what it is like to live in the Shrek Shack. The Wax Museum provides many more opportunities for children to have an enjoyable visit. They can try their luck as a rock band. The instruments and the illuminated stage are waiting. The ability to play the guitar or drums is not required. They dream of being a rock star. Now they can finally make it! The children are also in for a distorting mirror chamber, Santa\'s sleigh and a ten-minute video on the world's origins (available in the multimedia room). One of the rooms offers an art workshop where children can have their hand cast in wax and enjoy a variety of games and activities. Children can play in groups with activity organisers.</string>
    <string name="trams">Antique Trams</string>
    <string name="trams_contact">Theatre Square \n71 343 77 24 \nwww.tmw.com.pl/zabytkowe-tramwaje/</string>
    <string name="trams_description">Antique trams run in summer season, most often from May, every weekend (Saturday, Sunday) till 31st October. The trams run between the centre and Centennial Hall. For a part of a day the trams run around the monuments of Market Square and its surroundings. A professional guide talks about the history of these places during the course. The tourist trams are: „Jaś i Małgosia”, „Juliusz”, „Mikołaj” and „Strachotek”. The tram has its first stop at Theatre Square (between Wrocław Opera and Puppet Theatre). The ticket is valid to Centennial Hall (the last stop) or one can buy a round-trip ticket. Apart from a regular, seasonal tram line in Wrocław there is also a possibility to take a commercial ride.</string>
    <string name="carousel">Carousel in the Old Town Garden</string>
    <string name="carousel_contact">Old Town Garden</string>
    <string name="carousel_description">A beautiful, classical French, 19th century-style carousel is located near the playground for children in the Old Town Garden. It has electric drive, wooden horses and gondolas and hand-painted pictures of monuments of Wrocław. The carousel is primarily used by the children that play nearby.</string>
    <string name="jump_world">Jump World</string>
    <string name="jump_world_contact">15 Otmuchowska Street \n518 161 110 \nwww.jumpworld.pl/wroclaw/</string>
    <string name="jump_world_description">Jump World springboard parks guarantee thrilling experiences and top-level entertainment. It does not matter how old you are – everybody will find something for himself. It is an excellent place both for children, who can utilise their large amounts of energy in an interesting and completely new way, for young people, who can fulfil their craziest ideas, and for adults. The springboard park consists of the main arena, a volleyball zone, a basketball zone, an acrobatic track and a swimming pool with sponges.</string>
    <string name="polinka">Polinka</string>
    <string name="polinka_contact">2 Na Grobli Street\n71 320 46 10</string>
    <string name="polinka_description">A cableway Polinka has 380m, one ride over Oder lasts 2-2.5 minutes. The cars are about seven meters above the water. One station is located near C-13 building in Wyspiański Riverfront, the second one in Na Grobli Street, vis-à-vis GeoCentrum. There are two cars, each can carry 15 people. Almost 370 people use the cableway in one hour.</string>
    <string name="kolejkowo">Kolejkowo</string>
    <string name="kolejkowo_contact">20b Orląt Włoskich Square \n880 008 004 \nwww.kolejkowo.pl</string>
    <string name="kolejkowo_description">260 square metres of the model, 430m of rails, 15 locomotives, 60 railway wagons, 162 building including authentic buildings from Wrocław and Lower Silesia, 1600 figurines of people and animals, bridges, tunnels and water basins. The exhibition of railway models is divided into three parts. One of them is devoted to forest management and agriculture. One can see livestock and fully reconstructed agritourist household. In the second part there is Karpacz and Śnieżka mountain with the observatory on top. Next we can see Market Square with beautiful tenement houses, Świebodzki Railway Station and blocks in Żmigrodzka Street. In the central place we can see Kolejkowo.pl station with the replica of Szwajcarka mountain shelter.</string>
    <string name="hydropolis">Hydropolis</string>
    <string name="hydropolis_contact">19-21 Na Grobli Street \n71 340 95 15 \nwww.hydropolis.pl</string>
    <string name="hydropolis_description">Hydropolis, centre of knowledge about water, is located in the old building in Na Grobli Street. It is an old clean water tank, built in 1893. The attraction is for everyone, regardless of age. Modern multimedia ideas were applied during the construction. The whole exhibition has over 4 thousand square metres. In the room “The planet of water” we can learn about different theories of the origins of water in the Universe. The next rooms present a bit closer but equally interesting areas. One can get inside a bathyscaphe “Trieste”, in which two daredevils dived into the Mariana Trench in 1960. Right next to it, we can observe the creatures living in the oceans and seas, from several-metre long sharks to microbes. Every room has multimedia tablets with interesting details about ground-breaking discoveries of the underwater world, the nature of water and its use in the human life. We can also see the theme of water in religion and art. The interactive table with maps of Wrocław, for example during the Millennium Flood or the map of the city waterpipes, attracts both older and younger visitors. The visitors can enter every 30 minutes. Every ticket is sold for the certain hour, which corresponds to the hour of projection in “The planet of water” room - this is were the visit begins.</string>
    <string name="zoo">ZOO and Afrykarium</string>
    <string name="zoo_contact">1-5 Wróblewskiego Street \n71 348 30 24 \nwww.zoo.wroclaw.pl</string>
    <string name="zoo_description">The Zoo in Wrocław was created in 1865 and had a dozen hectares of surface. In the 50s of the 20th century it became twice bigger. Today on 33 ha live 10,502 animals, 11,382 species. ZOO in Wrocław is the oldest and the richest in fauna in Poland. It is possible to see the animals from every continent and environments, for example in Madagascar, Sahara or Europe Pavillons. In the last few years many new enclosures have been built, for example for bears and wolves. There are also new animals, among which very rare species like okapi. The youngest visitors of the Zoo can see: feeding of the animals: in summer - from April to October, in winter - from November to March; some animals in the yard can be fed by visitors. The food can be bought in the machines. Pony riding for children in summer on the Ranch for children under the age of 10; feeding can be watched everyday, the Zoo is open all year long, also on holidays. Wrocław Afrykarium is the only theme oceanarium devoted solely to the African fauna. On average, 2.5 thousand people visit it on the weekdays. The idea of Wrocław Afrykarium is to present the selected ecosystems of Africa. Afrykarium was built to the newest technologies, never used in Poland before.</string>
    <string name="aquapark">Aquapark</string>
    <string name="aquapark_contact">99 Borowska Street \n71 77 11 511 \nwww.aquapark.wroc.pl</string>
    <string name="aquapark_description">Aquapark Wrocław opened in February 2008. Until today it remains one of the best and most frequently visited water parks in Europe. It belongs to IAAPA, the world\'s largest organisation that associates Amusement Parks and Water Parks. The facility is owned by the Wrocław Municipality. Are you looking for a place in which you will never get bored and where you will be able to shed excess energy? Visit the Recreational Zone! Plenty of attractions and surprises are waiting for you here... This is the biggest zone in Aquapark, which offers numerous attractions (such as slides, jacuzzis, wave pool, ‘Lazy River’, Children Bay and outdoor pools). It also holds a separate part with a paddling pool and a slide for the youngest children. In Saunarium in the unique scenery, you can purify your body and mind, regain strength and gather energy to act. Everyone should visit the sauna garden, which holds Kelo and Bali, i.e. two Finnish saunas. Aroma ceremonies offer unique experience, and are held daily. Tuesdays in Saunarium are for women only."</string>
    <string name="four_denominations_district">Four Denominations District</string>
    <string name="four_denominations_district_contact">Pawła Włodkowica Street</string>
    <string name="four_denominations_district_description">The Four Denominations District – a place of meetings, dialogue, mutual respect and... numerous culinary experiences. The Four Denominations District is located in the centre of Wrocław, right next to Market Square. It consists of the area between the Kazimierza Wielkiego, Św. Mikołaja, Pawła Włodkowica and Św. Antoniego Street. It is not a regular, urban district but the unique atmosphere of the place caused that since 1995 it has been called Four Temples District, Four Denominations or Mutual Respect District. Its unique character derives from wonderful sacral architecture. In 300m, close to each other there are: Orthodox church of Nativity of Theotokos, church of St. Anthony of Padua - a Roman Catholic temple, The White Stork Synagogue and an Evangelical church of Divine Providence. In 1996 the Council of the Mutual Respect District was created in order to encourage cooperation between the religions. In 2005 the temples were connected with a “cultural route” and the area between them was included in the urban development plan. The District is considered a historical monument. On 29 November 2012 on the corner of the Kazimierza Wielkiego and Św. Antoniego Street the Cristal Planet statue was exhibited. The sculpture created by Ewa Rossano, an artist from Wrocław, became another symbol of the District. The Four Denominations District hosts many cultural and educational events. The Synagogue is a place of special meaning. It hosts many artistic events, every summer there are concerts and exhibitions organised under the name “Summer in The White Stork Synagogue”. A similar function has the nearby cinema New Horizons. It is the first cinema in Poland devoted to artistic films and hosts the most important film festivals in Wrocław. New Horizon Festival and American Film Festival became popular not only among Polish audience but also abroad. Multiple restaurants, cafés, pubs and music clubs situated in the Four Denominations District (for example in the beautiful patio of the Synagogue, surrounded by old walls) make it one of the most magical meeting place in Wrocław.</string>
    <string name="cathedral">Cathedral of St John Baptist</string>
    <string name="cathedral_contact">Cathedral Square \nwww.katedra.archidiecezja.wroc.pl</string>
    <string name="cathedral_description">Its history begins with the Congress of Gniezno when in 1000 three dioceses were created: wrocławska, krakowska and kołobrzeska. Cathedral of St. John Baptist was destroyed many times. Rebuilt in 1951, it was consecrated by Archbishop Stefan Wyszyński, Primate of Poland. Inside the cathedral we can admire precious statues and paintings: a triptych Dormition of Mary from 1552 (transported from Lubin), a pulpit (1723), oaken stall from 1662-1665 and many tombstones from Middle Ages, Mannerism and Baroque. The cathedral has 21 chapels, among which are: St. Elisabeth (1680-1686) and Electors’ Chapel (1716-1721), a work of an architect from Vienna, J. B. Frischer von Erlach. On the top of the tower there is a viewpoint where it is possible to get with the lift.</string>
    <string name="market_hall">Market Hall</string>
    <string name="market_hall_contact">17 Piaskowa Street \n71 343 84 57</string>
    <string name="market_hall_description">The Market Hall was built in 1905-1908 in the place of the 16th century Arsenal. Today, on two floors there are over 190 shops. It is not only a shopping centre, but also a tourist attraction. The two towers in Świętego Ducha Street hark back to the building of Arsenal. The authors of the building were Richard Plüddemann and Heinrich Küster. Küster is thought to invent the idea of using reinforced concrete to build the Hall, which was then an innovative solution. During Wolrd War II the building was not seriously damaged. At first the Red Army used it as stable but soon it returned to its original use. In the beginning of the 80s the Hall was directed by PSS Społem and was renovated. In 2016 its façade was revitalised. Today, it is a shopping centre not only for the Old Town citizens, but for everyone, including professors, nuns and priests from Ostrów Tumski. Many owners of the restaurants buy their products here. Market Hall belongs to the tourist trail and is visited by 30-35 groups a day. The building in Piaskowa Street has four floors, apart from the main hall with stalls and the gallery, there are two large cellars. A part of them serves as storerooms. In the cellar in ul. Piaskowa, under the clock tower, there is a restaurant.</string>
    <string name="four_domes_pavilion">Four Domes Pavilion</string>
    <string name="four_domes_pavilion_contact">1 Wystawowa Street \n71 712 71 82 \nwww.pawiloncztarechkopul.pl</string>
    <string name="four_domes_pavilion_description">The Four Domes Pavilivon was designed by a famous architect Hans Poelzig and built in the years 1912-1913 with the use of reinforced concrete, which was a novelty then. After almost seventy years the Four Domes Pavilion, one of the most interesting modernist buildings of Wrocław, became available for the public. On 25th June 2016 a new branch of the National Museum was opened here - the Museum of Contemporary Art. At first it served mainly as an exhibition centre - in 1913 it hosted an exhibition organised for the 100th anniversary of the victory over Napoleon. In 2006 it became part of the UNESCO World Heritage List. The refreshed building presents a collection of Polish contemporary art created by the most prominent artists of the second half of the 20th century and 21st century. Among others there are works of: Magdalena Abakanowicz, Paweł Althamer, Mirosław Bałka, Jerzy Bereś, Krzysztof Bednarski, Tadeusz Brzozowski, Waldemar Cwenarski, Stanisław Dróżdż, Józef Gielniak, Izabella Gustowska, Władysław Hasior, Józef Hałas, Tadeusz Kantor, Aleksander Kobzdej, Katarzyna Kozyra, Natalia Lach-Lachowicz, Alfred Lenica, Jan Lebenstein, Alfons Mazurkiewicz, Jerzy Nowosielski, Roman Opałka, Jerzy Rosołowicz, Henryk Stażewski, Władysław Strzemiński, Alina Szapocznikow, Jerzy Tchórzewski, Andrzej Wróblewski. The new exhibition centre will also present temporary exhibitions.</string>
    <string name="synagogue">The White Stork Synagogue</string>
    <string name="synagogue_contact">7 Włodkowica Street \n504 905 358</string>
    <string name="synagogue_description">The Synagogue was built in the place of the old tavern \"The White Stork Tavern\". Its designer was Carl Ferdinand Langhans. The first service took place in 1829. Since 1847 r. it was in possession of the liberal Jews but in 1872 it was taken by conservatives. Religious rule of separate places for men and women demanded new galleries for women. The renovation took place in 1905 and was performed by Paul and Richard Elrich. They designed Neo-Romantic galleries of reinforced concrete. During the 9th November 1938 Kristallnacht it was not set on fire because of the close buildings. The Hitlerists used it as a garage and a storehouse. After World War II the Jewish community reclaimed the temple but in 1966 it was closed because of bad technical state. Two years later all the services in the Synagogue were ceased. The building was in different hands, constantly being devastated. The Jewish community reclaimed it eventually in 1996. In May 1996 a renovation started and was finished in 2010. Foundation Bente Kahan was deeply involved in the process. Today in the Synagogue many religious events, concerts and shows take place.</string>
    <string name="centennial_hall">Centennial Hall</string>
    <string name="centennial_hall_contact">1 Wystawowa Street \n71 347 51 51 \nwww.halastulecia.pl</string>
    <string name="centennial_hall_description">Centennial Hall was recognised as one of the greatest architectonic achievements of the 20th century. It was designed to serve the citizens of Wrocław and the guests visiting the capital of Lower Silesia. The monumental building was opened in 1913 on the 100th anniversary of the Battle of Leipzig, won by the anti-French coalition against Napoleon Bonaparte. On this occasion, Wrocław hosted the Centennial Exhibition. Max Berg, the then city architect, designed a massive exhibition hall built with the use of the novel reinforced concrete technology. The dome of the Hall spans 65m and the building is 42m high. The main hall is surrounded by the corridors. It can fit 10 thousand people. The multifunctional space, unconventional construction, interesting and spacious location are only a few of the Halls assets. The Centennial Hall is currently one of the most wanted places to organise exhibitions, conferences, congresses, cultural and sporting events from Poland and from abroad. Its significance raised considerably in 2006 when the Hall became a part of UNESCO World Heritage List."</string>
    <string name="panorama">Panorama of the Battle of Racławice</string>
    <string name="panorama_contact">11 Purkyniego Street \n71 344 16 62 \nwww.panoramaraclawicka.pl</string>
    <string name="panorama_description">The painting present the Battle of Racławice in April 1794, in which Poles won over Russians. The monumental picture is 114m long and 15m high and was painted on the 100th anniversary of the victory. It was the idea of Jan Styka, a painter from Lvov, who invited among others Wojciech Kossak, Tadeusz Popiel, Teodor Axentowicz, Włodzimierz Tetmajer to work on the painting. The work took 9 months to finish. A rotunda with Panorama of the Battle of Racławice, built in Stryjeński Park, became one of the attractions of Lvov. The technology applied by the authors can be compared to the contemporary 3D technology. Special, panoramic perspective, lighting and scenography constructed in front of the picture make it look multidimensional. After World War II the Panorama of the Battle of Racławice came to Wrocław. For many years it was hidden in storeroom, mainly for political reasons - it shows the victory of Poles against Russians, and back then Poland was under the Soviet Union’s influence. Not until 1980 the works on the new rotunda started, the painting could be seen after 1985. Among the visitors were the Pope John Paul II and the Queen of the Netherlands, Beatrix. In 1987 the prime minister of China Zhao Ziyang was impressed by Panorama of the Battle of Racławice. Two years later, the first Chinese panorama was created, even bigger than the one in Wrocław. It presents the victory of the communists over the army of Kuomitang in 1948. Panorama became a popular tool of promotion of the most important events in the history of communist China. In the next years, over ten panoramas were created. During the visit, the viewers can listen to the history of the painting and the events presented in 16 languages (including Korean, Japanese, Croatian and Esperanto). For blind people there is an audio description available.</string>
    <string name="national_museum">National Museum</string>
    <string name="national_museum_contact">5 Powstańców Warszawy Square \n71 343 56 43 \nwww.mnwr.art.pl</string>
    <string name="national_museum_description">In the building in Powstańców Warszawy Square there are several permanent exhibitions, but some of the collections can be seen outside the Museum’s main building. Two of them are devoted to the medieval art - Silesian Stone Sculpture of 12-16th century (in renovation) and Silesian Art of 14-16th century (1st floor).  The expositions of the Polish Art of 17-19th century and European Art 15-20th century are on the 2nd floor. The most valuable pieces of art are: “Madonna with Jesus and St. John” by Agnolo Bronzino, “Winter landscape with ice skates and bird trap” by Pieter Bruegel the Younger and “Portrait of a Boy” by Jean Chardin. Some exhibits are in the old ducal residence, today\'s Museum of Silesian Piasts in Brzeg, where the permanent exhibition Silesian Art of 15-18th century is presented. An important part of the Museum\'s collection (furniture, portraits) is in the old City Hall, where the Museum of Municipal Art is located - it belongs to the Wrocław City Museum.</string>
    <string name="old_town_hall">Old Town Hall</string>
    <string name="old_town_hall_contact">50 Market Square \n71 347 16 91</string>
    <string name="old_town_hall_description">The tenement house called Old Town Hall is located in the eastern part of Market Square. The city council held their meetings there and used the rooms. King Augustus II the Strong used to reside there during is travels between Dresden and Warsaw. That is why it has the name Under the Polish King. The tenement house, as many in Market Square, was demolished at the beginning of the 20th century and a new building was built in its place. After World War II the tenement house was rebuilt but it looks different than the original from the 18th century, when it was in baroque style. Today in Old Town Hall there is the City Museum of Wrocław. Old Town Hall is a unique Gothic building in European architecture. It has 2 storeys, 3 parts with a rectangular building of the councils, which is attached to the northern wall and a square tower. Located in the city centre, it was being built for about 250 years (13 - 16th century). Around 1368 a clock was started and the bell has remained until today. The final look of the Town Hall was shaped by the great renovation in the years 1470-1480, when the building was enlarged almost by a half by attaching new rooms in the southern part and it got a more representative character. During the siege of Wrocław in 1945 Town Hall was severely damaged. It was restored to its previous glory by renovations and conservation. Since the very beginning the Town Hall has witnessed many important historical events and has been a representative building where the authorities invited their honourable guests. This tradition is still alive. The most important world leaders, monarchs, clergy and artists have been invited into the Town Hall. In the cellar of the building there is one of the oldest restaurants in Europe - the legendary Piwnica Świdnicka.</string>
    <string name="market_square">Market Square</string>
    <string name="market_square_contact">Market Square</string>
    <string name="market_square_description">Market Square has 3.8ha of surface and belongs to the biggest market places in Poland (the bigger ones are in Kraków and Olecko). However, the Late Gothic Town Hall with its 66m tower is the biggest building of this kind in Poland. In its underground functions Piwnica Świdnicka, one of the oldest restaurants in Europe. The edifice of the New Town Hall was built in the 19th century. This is where the authorities and the President have their offices. The old Town Hall belongs to the City Museum. Market Square is surrounded by the tenement houses funded by the patricians of Wrocław. The original building, stylistically different from the rest, is a modernist high rise built to the design of Heinrich Rump in 1930. After World War II Market Square went through several changes. In 1956 the statue of Aleksander Fredro was moved from Lvov. In the 70s the tram tracks were closed, the car traffic was heavily limited (the old petrol station was dismantled). The whipping post, destroyed during the war was restored to its original place. In 2000 a fountain was installed on Gołębi Square, in the western part of Market Square, and was called Zdrój from the name of the then President of Wrocław, Bogdan Zdrojewski. The whipping post, the fountain and Fredros statue are the most popular orientation and meeting points in Market Square. Another interesting spot are Hansel and Gretel, two tenement houses of the altarists (guardians of the altar in St. Elizabeth church) in the north-western part of Market Square. Market Square is also a place of Chirstmas Fairs, New Years Eve celebrations, religious, academic and military events. In 2012 Market Square was a big EURO fan zone, gathering as much as 30 thousand people. Curiosities: Market Square is 213m long and 178m wide. Market Square is surrounded by 60 tenement houses, including: Golden Sun, Griffins, Seven Electors, Blue Sun houses and Barasch shopping centre (today’s Feniks). Market Square is surrounded by 11 streets, it had 200 thousand people during the New Years Eve in 2013.</string>
    <string name="ossolineum">The Ossolineum</string>
    <string name="ossolineum_contact">37 Szewska Street \n71 344 44 71  \nwww.ossolineum.pl</string>
    <string name="ossolineum_description">The foundation Ossolineum was created in 1817 by Józef Maksymilian Ossoliński (1748-1826) in Lvov. By the will of the founder, the foundation was to consist of collections of books, manuscripts, numismatics and museum exhibits, offered by J. M. Ossoliński and lands to maintain the printing house. Ossolineum was also to publish its own scientific journal and take care of the young scientists. After World War II the borders changed and Lvov was not in Poland anymore. In 1944, a part of the collection was transported from Lvov - almost 11000 old prints, pictures, diplomas and manuscripts (the manuscript of “Pan Tadeusz”). The collections, hidden in Lower Silesia near Złotoryja, were transported to Wrocław in 1947. In the years 1946-1947 a part of the collection as given to Wrocław as “a gift of the Ukrainian nation to the Polish nation”.  217450 volumes were transported from Lvov, including 7068 manuscripts and 41505 old prints. It is estimated that around 70% of the collections remained in Lvov. Since 1990 Ossolineum has become more important as a national scientific and cultural institution. The collections are constantly growing, including valuable gifts and private collections (maps of Silesia from dr Tomasz Niewodniczański, medals, coins from Stanisław Garczyński; precious archives of Jan Nowak-Jeziorański, Tadeusz Żenczykowski, Władysław Bartoszewski). The collections of Ossolineum include around 1.700.000 units, among which there are prints, journals, manuscripts, documents, old prints, pictures, drawings, paintings, ex libris, medals, coins, stamps, maps and plans, posters, brochures, placards and microforms. Every year Ossolineum prepares big exhibitions of their vast and precious collections. Famous scientists, writers and artists participate in cultural meetings there. There are concerts and theatre performances too. Ossolineum provides its resources only in the reading room. The building was inherited after the Crusaders with Red Star. The Order received it from Duchess Agnieszka, a widow after Duke Henry II the Pious.</string>
    <string name="riverfront">University of Technology Riverfront</string>
    <string name="riverfront_contact">Wyspiański Riverfront</string>
    <string name="riverfront_description">Sporting and recreational terrain along the Oder next to Wyspiański Riverfront. The promenade which is to make it easier for citizens of Wrocław and tourists to get close to the river. The riverfront has a few hundred metres, it starts next to Polinka cableway and extends itself to the weir. There are volleyball courts, a beach, benches and places to rest on a blanket. The riverbank has devices for both big and small water units. There are places for kayaks and a slip for bigger boats. The whole riverfront is open, but a part of it is closed during at night.</string>
    <string name="stadium">Wrocław Stadium</string>
    <string name="stadium_contact">1 Śląska Street \n71 77 68 011 \nwww.stadionwroclaw.pl</string>
    <string name="stadium_description">Chinese lantern - that is how people think of the Wrocław Stadium. It is covered with elastic glass fibre material which makes it possible to light the stadium with different colours. The Stadium was built in 2011 on the occasion of UEFA EURO 2012. There are 43,863 seats, 102 places for the disabled. The Stadium was opened in September 2011 with the performance of George Michael and Symphonica project. The same month there was a boxing fight of Tomasz Adamek and Vitali Klitschko and in October Monster Truck event was held on the Stadium. Both WKS Śląsk Wrocław and Polish national team play their matches on Wrocław Stadium. But it is not only football that happens there. Every year there are many wonderful concerts and various entertainment and sporting events. Everyday the Stadium offers various services: recreational, such as fitness club, go-kart track or jumping on Dream Jump lines, and rents offices and the all-year working Event Centre for companies.</string>
    <string name="partynice">Horse Racing Track Partynice</string>
    <string name="partynice_contact">2 Zwycięska Street \n 71 339-83-64 \nwww.torpartynice.pl</string>
    <string name="partynice_description">The Track in Partynice, designed by R. Jürgens from Hamburg, was opened in 1907, on the 75th anniversary of Silesian Horse Breeders and Horse Racing Association. Partynice replaced the track in Szczytniki. The most important runs that take place in Partynice - Great Wrocław Run - 5 y. o. horses, obstacles, 5000 m with 175 thousand zloty and Great Partynicki Run - 4 y. o. horses, hurdles, 4200 m with 105 thousand zloty and 4 runs of A category: Lira - Oaks Prize, President of Wrocław Award (4 y. o. horses, 2400 m), Ruten Prize (3 y. o. horses, 2600 m) and Constelation Prize (3 y. o. mares, 2400 m). In Partynice there are also family picnics, dog competitions and other events.</string>
    <string name="slodowa_island">Słodowa Island</string>
    <string name="slodowa_island_contact">Słodowa Island</string>
    <string name="slodowa_island_description">Słodowa Island belongs to the Oder archipelago located to the north of Market Square. Apart from Słodowa, the other Wrocław Islands are: Bielarska, Młyńska, Piasek, Daliowa and Tamka. The Island used to be built-up but during World War II most of the buildings were destroyed, only a six-storey tenement house survived. The picnic season begins on the 21st of March when the Island is crowded with students of secondary and upper-secondary schools celebrating Truant Day (firs day of spring). All year long the Island is under the “reign” of students. During summer weekends there are many attractions on the Island: on Fridays and Saturdays open-air cinema, Saturday concerts, board games, sport activities, on Sundays dance classes or open-air library. In the tourist season one can buy something to eat and drink.</string>
    <string name="japanese_garden">Japanese Garden</string>
    <string name="japanese_garden_contact">Mickiewicza Street \nwww.ogrod-japonski.wroclaw.pl</string>
    <string name="japanese_garden_description">It is one of the most popular places for walks. Apart from a few hundreds of original plants, trees, bushes and flowers, there are also Japanese buildings: the gate and the tea pavilion. One of the attractions of the Garden is a pond with enormous carps and other species of fish. The Garden often hosts events like tea perking, concerts and open-air happenings. The Japanese Garden was created in the beginning of the 20th century, on the occasion of the Global Exhibition in 1913. It was an initiative of count Fritz von Hochberg, who employed a Japanese gardener Mankichi Arai. After the Exhibition it was dismantled but the plants and the arrangement of alleys and the pond remained the same. The idea of renewing the Japanese Garden in Wrocław appeared in the 90s. The reconstruction lasted three years, the specialists from Japan came to assist, but the Garden did not survived for long. Two months after the inauguration, the Garden was destroyed by the flood. 70% of the plants were lost. The next opening of the Japanese enclave took place in October 1999.</string>
    <string name="fountain">Multimedia Pountain</string>
    <string name="fountain_contact">1 Wystawowa Street \n71 347 50 47</string>
    <string name="fountain_description">Wrocław Multimedia Fountain is the biggest fountain in Poland and one of the biggest in Europe. It has 1 ha of surface, 800 lights, 300 water jets and 3 fire jets in the basin. It was initiated on 4th June 2009 on the occasion of the 20th anniversary of the first free elections in the postwar Poland. Located in the beautiful Szczytnicki Park, near the Centennial Hall and Wrocław Congress Centre, attracts many Polish and foreign tourists. The basin of Pergola has 300 water jets, which create geysers, water mists, spurts and many other shapes. The water installation is synchronised with 800 lights - light, water and music together create spectacular shows. The shows take place every hour, everyday, and vary in length. The Multimedia Fountain plays classical and pop music, for example Madonna, Daft Punk, but one can also hear calm, relaxing music. During the special night shows there are animations, photos and films projected on water. Many of them show the important events from the history of the city and Poland. On the occasion of EURO 2012 the pictures showed the greatest successes of the Polish national team.</string>
    <string name="ostrow_tumski">Ostrów Tumski</string>
    <string name="ostrow_tumski_contact">Cathedral Square</string>
    <string name="ostrow_tumski_description">Surrounded by the river Oder, the old burgh, the origin of the city, has fantastic architecture. The greatest ones are the Gothic St. John Baptist cathedral, rebuilt after World War II and Holy Cross church. There is the Archdiocese Museum there, the oldest historically continuous museum in Wrocław - for over 100 years it has gathered sacral art, which was excluded from cult use and has great historical and artistic value. Among the exhibits one can find Henrykowska Book from 13th-14th century, which contains the first sentence written in Polish.</string>
    <string name="szajnochy">Szajnochy 11</string>
    <string name="szajnochy_contact">11 Szajnochy Street \n71 342 30 62 \nwww.szajnochy11.pl</string>
    <string name="szajnochy_description">Traditional, elaborated sushi of the finest, natural vegetables and a common denominator is the finest fish and seafood. Behind the bar the tool used is yanagi-ba, in the kitchen it’s sous-vide. Szajnochy 11 offers the finest fish and seafood which comes from the Dutch fish market. The restaurant joins two worlds: Japanese and Polish-Scandinavian cuisine. Important elements in the restaurant are vegetables which are imported from the local farmers or chosen by the workers at the market in the Netherlands.</string>
    <string name="vega">Vega</string>
    <string name="vega_contact">27a Market Square \n71 344 39 34</string>
    <string name="vega_description">Vega is one of the oldest Polish bars for vegetarians, it exists since 1987. Now it’s 100% vegan. The meals are prepared from scratch, made only of plant products: fresh fruit and vegetables, legumes, groats, nuts, seeds and herbs. They don’t use half-products, canned food or any products of animal origin. The menu also offers gluten-free dishes and meals for diabetics.</string>
    <string name="spiz">Restaurant and mini-brewery Spiż</string>
    <string name="spiz_contact">2 Market Square City Hall \n71 344 72 25 \nwww.spiz.pl/wroclaw</string>
    <string name="spiz_description">Mini-brewery Spiż since the 90s has occupied the basement in which there was pre-war “Ratuszowa”. A brewery opened in the underground is one of the favourite places to relax for the people from Wrocław and guests. Despite the beer that is brewed there, according to the original recipie, in the basements of the Town Hall there is a restaurant. On 27 June 1992 Spiż was opened as the first mini-brewery and restaurant in Poland. In Wrocław’s Town Hall and its historic interiors brewing of “Spiż” beer began in front of the clients. Its recipe was developed by Bogdan Spiż. In the beautifully renovated, historic indoors, a production unit has been created which consists of a restaurant, mini-brewery, summer garden, shop with souvenirs and beer pub. It is where we position a wort kettle of an interesting form and a lauter tun. Other technological equipment may be seen through the glass walls. Today 6 types of beers are produced in Spiż. Brown bread covered with labelled lard served with each beer is also widely known and enjoyed by the guests.</string>
    <string name="novocaina">Novocaina</string>
    <string name="novocaina_contact">13 Market Square \n71 343 69 15 \nwww.novocaina.com</string>
    <string name="novocaina_description">Novocaina is one of the most recognised and trusted Wrocław restaurants. The venue offers a rich variety of traditional Mediterranean dishes and a selection of regional dished from northern Italy. The décor has remained the same since the restaurant\'s opening and still inspires designers with classical style and subtle modern undertones blended into Art Nouveau interiors. The restaurant exudes warmth and offers a unique and atmospheric journey through styles and eras.Their respect for tradition is epitomised by a wood-fired oven in which a variety of dishes are prepared.</string>
    <string name="jadka">JaDka</string>
    <string name="jadka_contact">24/25 Rzeźnicza Street \n71 343 64 61 \nwww.jadka.pl</string>
    <string name="jadka_description">JaDka is located in the theatrical corner of the city, next to the medieval market square and for many years has invited to one of the most beautiful and historic interiors of Wrocław. jaDka in Rzeźnicza 24-25 in Wrocław is a special place which alludes to the traditional, Polish manor house and noble cuisine where next to the dishes made of boar or venison there are also dumplings or slices of country black pudding. Magic of this place, light, flowers and the professional staff provide the maximum comfort while tasting Polish cuisine with the elements of Mediterranean cuisine.</string>
    <string name="szynkarnia">Szynkarnia</string>
    <string name="szynkarnia_contact">15 Św. Antoniego Street \n607 333 432 \nwww.szynkarnia.com.pl</string>
    <string name="szynkarnia_description">Original Menu and wide choice of beers and refreshing non-alcoholic drinks makes Szynkarnia and interesting place for the afternoon meeting with your friends. All the unique beers from Poland and the whole World from beer dispensers, podpłomyks, farm cooked meats and cheeses, sourdough bread and homemade cookies.</string>
</resources>
